Stanley Asoku Hayford

Accra, Greater Accra Region, Ghana



hayfordstanley@gmail.com



+233270048319



linkedin.com/in/stanley-asoku-hayford-320b67106 https://hayfordstanley.vercel.app



Summary

5 years of total experience with 4 years of Building frontend apps using React JS, 4 years of experience building Server-Side applications using NodeJS and Express, and 2 years of experience building mobile apps using React Native.

I also have 3 years of experience building backend servers using Go Lang and Fibre framework.

Experienced UI developer trained in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, and Material Design.

Experienced in building backend servers using NodeJS and Go Programming Language.

Developed a crowdfunding app using React Native, NodeJS, and MongoDB.

Developed an E-commerce application that enabled vendors to sell their products and consumers to buy products. Built a hospital management system that enabled hospitals to manage their patients and doctors.

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

Dev Track

Jan 2022 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Design websites, mobile apps and APIs using REACTJS, react native and Nodejs

Full Stack Engineer

SORPHISE

Jan 2019 - Jun 2022 (3 years 6 months)

Translated Wireframes and PSD Designs into functional web apps.

Bound UI elements to JavaScript object models

Created RESTful services with Node.js

Created Unit and Integration tests to ensure the quality of code

Changed requests and feature requests

Wrote reusable, testable, and efficient code

Designed and implemented low-latency, high-availability, and performant applications

Implemented security and data protection



Full-stack Developer

Vien Health

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021 (7 months)

Regularly inspected server code for speed optimization.

Conceptualized and implemented solutions for data storage.

Improved the quality of the team's code through writing unit tests and automation.

Collaborated and worked closely with the product and design team to understand better the end-user requirements.

Configured the backend usability of all front side application.

Provided code documentation and other inputs to technical documents

Integrated user-facing elements developed by front-end developers with server-side logic

Provided code documentation and other inputs to technical documents

Participated in code reviews

Troubleshooting and debugging to optimise performance



Teaching Assistant

Kwame Nkrumah' University of Science and Technology, Kumasi Sep 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year)

Education



Kwame Nkrumah' University of Science and Technology, Kumasi

Computer engineering, Computer Engineering 2013 - 2017

⊗^{₹™} Zero To Mastery Academy

Licenses & Certifications

- **Basic Problem Solving Skills** HackerRank
- Hackerrank Basic Python Certification HackerRank
- Hackerrank Basic Javascipt Certification HackerRank
- Java Basic Certification HackerRank
- M001 MongoDB Certification MongoDB
- M121: The MongoDB Aggregation Framework MongoDB
- **Docker for absolute beginners Hands on** KodeKloud

- (A) Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- **Output** Python for beginners Learn all the basics of python Python for beginners Udemy
- Learn Go Course Codecademy
- Learn PHP Course Codecademy
- **Learn TypeScript Course** Codecademy

Skills

Algorithms • Web Development • Unit Testing • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • TypeScript • React.js • Google Material Design • Responsive Web Design